

Sanjay Dhall

Sanjay.dhall@yahoo.com +91 9810302604

CULINARY PHILOSOPHY & INFLUENCES:

My cooking style draws upon the techniques and flavors from cultures around the world but is rooted in classic French traditions. I endeavor to balance European traditionalism with Asian minimalism & American ingenuity. The results are like no other, a highly personal cuisine that excites the palate & soothes the soul.

I stress on the innovative use of healthy ingredients, free-range meats, tree ripened fruits, and organic vegetables form the heart of my cooking.

It is my belief that food should be appreciated and shared with joy using all our senses: vision, hearing, touching, smelling, and tasting. This is luxury. Let's appreciate what we have and utilize our sources of food to the best of our ability.

HIGHLIGHTS:

2014, Embassy of France, New Delhi, India Inducted into the Order of Disciples of Escoffier

Georges Blanc, Vonnas, France, May 2005 Onwards
Developed fleet wide fine dining menus for Carnival Cruise Lines
with Chef Blanc during the summer. Perfected cooking skills with
Georges Blanc to gain fresh insight into sauces. Blanc operates six
restaurants in France and has maintained a coveted
three- Michelin-star rating for the last 25 years.

Jean Pierre Vigato, Paris, France, May-June 1999
Trained with Chef Vigato in Paris in his 3 star Michelin restaurant.
Worked as a saucier, rotisserie, and vegetable cook to gain valuable insights into French cuisine. I was involved in the minutest details of operation from buying fresh produce at Les Halles in Paris at 4 am to growing our own herbs in the garden and indoor.

Charlie Trotter, Chicago, USA, May – June 1998 Worked at Charlie Trotters for 4 weeks in all sections of the kitchen Prepared special meals for guests of Chef Trotter and gained insight into a keen sense of perfection, and discipline required to succeed as a restaurateur under the master Chef himself.







WORK EXPERIENCE:

Independent Ventures and Entrepreneurship Ongoing Since 2015

Entrepreneur, Partner - Qla, New Delhi, www.qla.co.in

Owner, Creator- Daaya Boutique Villas, Assagaon, Goa, https://www.rftpm.in/villa-daaya.php

CARNIVAL CRUISE LINES, Miami, FI

Sr. Director, Culinary and Food Operations

November 2019 - March 2022.

Role augmented with oversight over compliance to various regulatory requirements, in addition to previous responsibilities

- Successfully inducted Mardi Gras into the fleet. A new class of vessels that is largest in the fleet that required a complete rethink the operations and product delivery
- Emerils opened the first of its kind on a Cruiseline by successfully inducting the Brand, its cuisine and its to the Carnival fold
- Big Chicken opened up Shaquille O'Neil's brand for Carnival and successfully inducted it into our operations to rave reviews
- Rudy's Sea Grill designed the concept and cuisine for the restaurant and took it to execution.
- Created and executed Chibang, the lines first dual cuisine inclusive dining restaurant that serves both mexican and chinese cuisines side by side
- Carnival Kitchen revenue based, participatory, guided cooking lessons set in a custom-built venue, the product was initially created for Panorama and was further refined and developed to a constantly sold-out success that it is today
- Created and executed Streets Eats, an open-air dining location that mimics market style food stalls.
- Inducted Guy Fieri's Pig and Anchor BBQ and Cucina del Capitano into the inclusive dining stream of the food operation with complete redesign of the menu, its production and restaurant operations.
- Java Blue Café created and executed an all-day dining quick service menu for the outlet.







CARNIVAL CRUISE LINES, Miami, FI

Director, Culinary and Food Operations

November 2018 – November 2019

Assumed overall responsibility for the entire food operations department as Director and incorporates the following additions and empowerments to previous role

- Oversight and Control over \$350 million cost operations
- Oversight and control of \$53 million annual revenue operation
- Responsible for all Food Operations Mangers and Executive chefs of the fleet.
- Oversight over planning budgets for cost and revenue operations
- Oversight over food purchasing operations
- Planning and executing food operations programme for upcoming and proposed new builds
- Human Resource Planning and Talent Development

CARNIVAL CRUISE LINES, Miami, FI

Director - Culinary

October 2015 - November 2018

Took over as Directory Culinary Development to streamline operations and develop new concepts for upcoming new build projects. The role oversees all aspects of culinary arts operations onboard and shore side.

Concepts created as below

- Guy Fiery Ping and Anchor BBQ research, conceptualization and execution of the BBQ product line in line with the collaborators vision
- Seafood Shack A revenue option that showcases fresh classical American seafood dishes cooked to order
- Sushi @ Sea a short order venue that percolates the Bonsai Sushi across the fleet
- Revitalizations a complete overhaul of the following venues to bring them to par with industry standards and their own natural evolution
 - Steak House (Revenue)
 - Cucina del Capitano (Revenue)
 - Deli
 - Teppanyaki
 - Sit Down Breakfast at the Restaurants
 - Chefs Table Restaurant / Gastronomy Center
 - Guys Fiery Smoke House Brewhouse Restaurant (Revenue)







ACCOR HOTELS

Aerocity, New Delhi, INDIA

Culinary Director

November 2013 - September 2015

Creation and execution of dinning concepts, selection of teams, designing and sourcing of service ware, menu concepts, and streamlining purveyors

Conceptualization and Execution as follows:

- Deli Café Italian & French inspired café that serves, charcuterie, pastrami panini, croissants, brioche, handcrafted Napolitano pizza, quiche, durum wheat ravioli, unique combinations for lasagna, macaroon, tiramisu, éclairs and much more
- Square Spanish & Mediterranean influenced family style Restaurant, serving Breakfast, Lunch, Brunch & Dinner, Amazing ice creams, Modern Desserts
- Delhi Bloom A tribute to local Farmers & local purveyors, "FARM TO TABLE": Concept, very organic service ware, bull horn, wood, slates, hydroponic farm grown produce, effective balance of local and fair trade, imported meat
- Khao Bisutoro Modern Asian Bisutoro, featuring most popular food from Thailand, Vietnam, China, and India presented in minimalist modern service ware from BCN55 from Barcelona & Local Artisans

CARNIVAL CRUISE LINES, Miami, FI

Director Culinary Development

March 2012 - July 2013

The Primary goal of the role remains the same as Executive Chef Culinary Development, it encompasses more responsibilities towards planning and organizing and co-coordinating the deployment of Funship 2.0 programme through the fleet, this introduces the fleet to new cuisine concepts and operations and is a comprehensive revision to bring the fleet at par with shore side vacation destinations in keeping with Carnivals vision of offering a complete vacations destinations, a synopsis of it follows

- George Lopez' Punchliner Comedy Brunch Developing and deploying a brunch showcasing the comedy programme designed by the Famous Actor and Comedian
- Cucina Del Capitano Standalone Italian restaurant based around a revenue operation, home style and authentic Italian cuisine capturing nuances of Italy cherished by the Italian captains of the fleet.
- Fahrenheit 555 A revised steak house programme based around USDA prime beef showcased along with great seafood, a cutting-edge technique and Avant – grade cuisine.







- Ji-Ji Asian Kitchen A pursuit in Asian cuisine, introducing patrons to a fine balance between classical cuisines of China and its modern adaptations.
- Guy Fieri's Burger Joint Integration of the celebrity chef's concept into CCL operation and making it as one of most successful Celebrity Chef ventures at sea
- Blue Iguana Cantina A part of lido transformation by introducing a Mexican Themed outlet, focused on fresh ingredients and live tortillas, the programme extends from breakfast to late at night
- Bonsai Sushi Conversion of all the current sushi bars in the fleet to a free-standing Japanese cuisine dining programme at the promenade of the ships in the fleet
- Taste Bar A promenade location show casing various new and emerging cuisine concepts as small plates, capturing attention of the guests and promoting various food locales
- Cherry on the Top A complete revision of the candy and chocolate programme onboard designed to attract foot fall at the location and assist in enhancing revenue at the location by sales and merchandising

CARNIVAL CRUISE LINES, Miami, FI

Executive Chef Culinary Development

Dec 2002 - March 2012

Head of the Culinary Development – a team of 40 talented chefs at CCL. The team spearheads any and every form of change in the culinary arena of Carnival Cruise Lines: from introduction of new menus based on current trends, standardization of procedures, lean F&B control, to assessment of monthly food orders worth \$1 million per ship.

- Lead the support team from CCL for pre- opening of Queen Mary-II, CUNARD, our sister concern.
- Launch and tie up with Chef Georges Blanc for Carnival ships. Planning and implementation of all VVIP dinner, & functions: Chaine de rotisseurs, Food & Wine magazine dinners.
- Managed the opening team for all new ships for Carnival. It is an overall responsibility for the job from pre- planning stage of design of kitchen, to recruitment, selection, training of personnel, and finally smooth opening and functioning of the first few cruises. I have leaded the pre-opening team for the last 12 Carnival ships.
- Procurement of chinaware, glassware, and buffet props for entire Carnival fleet. Including summoning new designers from Thailand to custom designed flatware for fine dining restaurants, and uniforms for F&B personnel.





CARNIVAL CRUISE LINES, Miami, FI

Senior Chef

June 1998 - Dec 2002

- Responsible for looking after the quality of food fleet wide
- Responsible for all New Ship openings, from selecting the manpower (both Kitchen Management and work force), designing menus, etc.
- Entrusted with the overall responsibility of the introduction and implementation of the galley operations for the soon-to-be launched luxury super liner The M/S Glory. I was instrumental in for designing the Concept, Menu and Presentation etc. for a New Fine Dining Restaurant within Carnival ships.
- Managed a team of 20 Chef de Cuisine & their respective full team (each team consists of approx. 100 cooks) positioned across the fleet.

CARNIVAL CRUISE LINES, Miami, FL

Chef De Cuisine

Nov 1996- June 1998

- Responsible for the overall Food Production operation on the assigned ship, producing up to 12,000 meals a day.
- Managed the kitchen manpower of 120 cooks, 3 Sous Chefs and 5 Chef De Parties
- Financial budgeting and management of food consumption of up to \$ 2,40,000 a week
- Menu planning, food ordering & costing and other technical and administrative aspects

CARNIVAL CRUISE LINES, Miami, FL

Sous Chef

May 1993- Nov 1996

- Joined Seachest Associates, a Food & Beverage department of Carnival Cruise Lines as a Sous Chef Trainee in May 1993.
 Was confirmed as Sous Chef in the month
- of January 1994. Directly responsible for supervising the Food Production activity on the floor of the house. Responsible for assisting Chef de Cuisine in his administrative roles.







MILK FOOD LIMITED, New Delhi, India

Chef-de-Partie

1991 –1993

Worked as a supervisor for a local Indian fast-food chain with daily sales of \$12000 in 2 outlets. Was instrumental in introducing fusion of Indian and European food items on the menu.

TAJ HOTELS & RESORTS, New Delhi, India

Various Capacities

1985 - 1991

Worked in different capacities in the kitchen from an apprentice, to breakfast cook, saucier, vegetable cook, fish cook, roast cook, and finally to a Commis I in the best fine dining restaurant in India.

EDUCATION & PROFESSIONAL TRAINING

- Summer Internship in Chef Marco Pierre White's, 2 Michelin star restaurant "Oak Room".
- United States Public Health seminar for sanitation and public health procedures.
- MHA course in Austria Salzburg for 3 weeks. Completed with A Grade (91%)
- Attended custom-made seminars for CCL on Food & Beverage from Johnson & Wales University, Miami, Florida.
- Diploma in Culinary Arts in the year 1985 from New Delhi University securing a first Class.
- Pre University in the year 1982 from Punjab University securing a second Class.

REFERENCES

CHEF GEORGE BLANC Coveted 3 Michelin Star Chef (Please contact his Director Operations, to be put through to Chef)

Relais & Châteaux Georges BLANC Antoine MAILLON DIRECTEUR DES OPERATIONS 01540 VONNAS- FRANCE Ligne directe + 33 4 74 50 90 40 Mobile + 33 6 25 49 6156 amaillon@georgesblanc.com

CHEF GUY FIERI Celebrity Chef and Restauranteur

Please reach out to Reid Strathearn to be put through to Chef Guy. guy@guyfieri.com reid@guyfieri.com +1 415 425 6454

Disciples () Escoffier INTERNATIONAL

Le Conseil Magistral des Disciples C Escoffier International

en son grand chapitre du 13 Mars 2044

tenu à NEW DELHI - INDE

décerne solennellement le titre de Disciple

a M onsieur SANJAY DHALL

J. Committee

Le Président de la Délégation

Squad for June



30 May 1998

Regarding: Sanjay Dhall

Mr. Sanjay Dhall completed a four week, non-paid, stage at Charlie Trotter's Restaurant from May 1, 1998 to May 30, 1998. During his stay with us Chef Charlie Trotter and myself have found Mr. Dhall to be an extremely competent worker with a great attention for detail. His attitude was always positive and he was a very dedicated worker. During his stay with us Mr. Dhall prepared a few courses for special guests and they were very well received. If he did not have to return to his job at Carnival Cruise Lines, we would have offered to extend his stay at Charlie Trotter's.

We recommend him with the highest regards.

Sincer#ly,

Charlie Trotter and Sari Zernich

816 West Armitage Avenue, Chicago, Illinois 60614 Tel (773) 248.6228 Fax (773) 248.6088



122, avenue de Villiers 75017 Paris Tel. 01 43 80 19 66 Fax 01 44 40 09 57

API CIUS

122, avenue de Villiers 75017 Paris Tel.: 01 43 80 19 66 Fax: 01 44 40 09 57 Capital 264 000 F RCS Paris B 582 034 849 RELAIS & CHATEAUX



GEORGES BLANC

December 2006

To Whom It May Concern:

This is to introduce Sanjay Dhall who I know from December 2005. During this period of professional and personal interaction, I found him to be very diligent, disciplined, talented, patient, and skilful Chef.

His people and task management skills are par excellence. He has been overlooking my programme on board the Carnival Cruise Lines for the last 18 months. During this time he managed the training and development of CCL chefs at my restaurant in Paris, implemented menus, and managed the financial aspect of the business.

During my visit to the ships I've been overwhelmed to see the vast but very intricate operation he has been running on 22 ships.

I cannot end this note without mentioning about Sanjay's creations in Supper Club (Fine Dining Restaurant on board Carnival Cruise Lines Super Deluxe 8 ships). Degustation Menu is really very creative and each course is very well balanced. One of the best meals I have ever had.

Over and top he is a great human being who has his personal presence felt and missed where ever he goes

I have no hesitation in recommending Chef Sanjay Dhall.

I wish him all the best in his future Endeavour

 ${\mathscr B}$ Regards

Georges BLANC





